Ann Cottrell Free Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speeches and Writings, 1899-2018 (Box 25-50)
  - Subjects (Box 43)
    - Early writings, 1933-1942, undated, (2 folders) (Box 47)
    - Environmental concerns, 1956-1981, (3 folders) (Box 47)
    - Foreign affairs, 1947-1966 (Box 47)
    - "Foreign places," circa 1940s (Box 47)
    - Germany, 1947-1948, 1954 (Box 47)
    - Greece, Yugoslavia, Macedonia, Bulgaria (with photographs), 1947 (Box 47)
    - Louisa, Va., 1959, 1980 (Box 47)
    - Mongolia; "Road to Xanadu," 1947-1999 (Box 48)
    - Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1938-1958 (Box 48)
    - Takla Makan Desert, China; Lop Nur, China, 1952, 1965-1967, (4 folders) (Box 48)
    - Truman, Harry S., 1943-1945, 1980 (Box 48)
    - Ungern-Sternberg, Roman; Mongolia, 1955-1966 (Box 48)
    - Ungern-Sternberg, Roman; Mongolia, 1955-1966 (Box 49)
    - Unpublished, 1937-1956, (2 folders) (Box 49)
    - "Vegetarian Life," circa 1975 (Box 49)
    - Whirligig (with James Free), 1955, 1961-1962 (Box 49)
    - Women (Box 49)
      - "Foreign women," 1955-1956, undated (Box 49)
      - Government appointments and civil servants, 1950-1955, (2 folders) (Box 49)
      - Industry, 1942-1943, 1960 (Box 50)
      - Medicine, 1943-1951 (Box 50)
      - Military, 1942-1944 (Box 50)
      - Politics, 1948-1970, (2 folders) (Box 50)
      - United States Congress, 1941, 1954-1955, 1965 (Box 50)
      - Women Accepted for Volunteer Emergency Service (WAVES), 1943-1944 (Box 50)
      - Women's Auxiliary Army Corps (with photographs), 1941-1944, (2 folders) (Box 50)
      - Women's Royal Navy Service (with photographs), 1942 (Box 50)
      - World War II, general, 1941-1943 (Box 50)
- Subject File, 1904-2007 (Box 51-223)
  The bulk of the collection, the Subject File series largely consists of working and background files that document the breadth of topics Free wrote about throughout her career. Most of the files in the series relate to animals and animal welfare issues including humane societies, animal legislation, laboratory animals, farm animals, pets, wildlife, ethics, and specifically the relationships between humans and animals. Other significant files focus on topics Free revisited throughout her life and wrote about in detail. These include extensive files on famine and politics in post war China, Eleanor Roosevelt and her relationship with the female press corps, the “reverence for life” philosophy of Albert Schweitzer, and Rachel Carson and her impact on environmental activism. Many of these files contain writings, correspondence, notes, speeches, diaries, photographs, and research files. The series also documents Free’s involvement with the Albert Schweitzer Fellowship, Mrs. Roosevelt’s Press Conference Association, National Press Club (previously the Washington Press Club), Rachel Carson Council, Society of Woman Geographers, and many local and national humane societies and animal welfare associations. Other noteworthy individuals documented within the series include Elisabeth De Croÿ, Zhou Enlai, Ellen Glasgow, Temple Grandin, Lister Hill, Mary Hornaday, Ruby Black, Edouard Nies-Berger, Malvina Stephenson, Christine Stevens, and Ernest P. Walker.
  Material types include clippings, notes, correspondence, writings, printed matter, and photographs.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - 4-H clubs, 1967-1999, (3 folders) (Box 51)
  - Academy of American Poets; Poetry Society of America, 1983-1988 (Box 51)
  - Action 81, Inc.; Action for Life, 1975-1990 (Box 51)
  - Agenda: News Magazine of the Animal Rights Network, 1987-1997 (Box 51)
  - Agriculture and farms, 1959-1978 (Box 51)
  - Agriculture and farms, 1959-1978, (3 folders) (Box 52)
  - Airplane issues, 1966-1968 (Box 52)
  - Alabama, animal issues, 1960-1983, (3 folders) (Box 52)
  - Alaskan Safari (film), 1971 (Box 52)
  - Alternatives to animal experiments, 1967-1998 (Box 52)
  - Alternatives to animal experiments, 1967-1998, (7 folders) (Box 53)
  - Alternatives to animal experiments, 1967-1998, (6 folders) (Box 54)
  - Ambivalence, 1958-1998 (Box 54)
  - Ambivalence, 1958-1998, (3 folders) (Box 55)
  - American Humane Association, 1940-1996, (3 folders) (Box 55)
  - American Humane Association, 1940-1996, (2 folders) (Box 56)
  - American Newspaper Women's Club, 1952-2003, (2 folders) (Box 56)
  - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (ASPCA), 1971-1997 (Box 56)
  - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (ASPCA), 1971-1997, (2 folders) (Box 57)
  - Animal behavior, 1962-1995, (4 folders) (Box 57)
  - Animal breeding, cats and dogs, 1960-1998 (Box 57)
  - Animal Charity of Ohio, 1969-1974 (Box 58)
  - Animal dealers, 1966-1991, (2 folders) (Box 58)
  - Animal experiments, 1958-1999, (4 folders) (Box 58)
  - Animal experiments, 1958-1999, (2 folders) (Box 59)
  - Animal/human bond, 1973-1991, (3 folders) (Box 59)
  - Animal laws and legislation, 1937-2000, (2 folders) (Box 59)
  - Animal laws and legislation, 1937-2000 (Box 60)
  - Animal laws and legislation, Washington, D.C., 1965-1967 (Box 60)
  - Animal Legal Defense Fund, 1984-1995, (2 folders) (Box 60)
  - Animal Liberation Front, 1978-1996 (Box 60)
  - Animal organizations directory, 1988 (Box 60)
  - Animal organizations directory, Maryland and Washington, D.C., 1986-1987 (Box 60)
  - Animal poems, 1963-1997 (Box 60)
  - Animal Protection Institute of America, 1961-1980 (Box 61)
  - Animal rights, 1944-2001, (6 folders) (Box 61)
  - Animal rights, 1944-2001, (2 folders) (Box 62)
  - Animal rights activists, 1962-2005, (2 folders) (Box 62)
  - "Animal rights and environment buttons," circa 1970-circa 1990 See OV 3, same heading (Box OV 3)
  - "Animal rights" history, 1916-1995 (Box 62)
  - Animal Rights Information and Education Series Newsletter, 1990-1993 (Box 62)
  - Animal Rights Information and Education Series Newsletter, 1990-1993 (Box 63)
  - Animal trapping, 1960-1996, (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - Animal wastes, 1968-1974 (Box 63)
  - Animal Welfare Act (Box 63)
    - "Animals for Scientific Progress: Origins of the 1966 Laboratory Animal Welfare Act" by Vicki McKinney Daitch, 1993 (Box 63)
    - "Ann's animal bill," 1964-1965, 1999 (Box 63)
    - Articles and writings by Free, 1959-1993 (Box 63)
    - Foley, Thomas, amendment, 1970-1976 (Box 63)
    - Foley, Thomas, amendment, 1970-1976 (Box 64)
    - Miscellany, 1960-1989, (6 folders) (Box 64)
    - Miscellany, 1990-1996, (2 folders) (Box 65)
    - Violations, 1970-1990 (Box 65)
  - Animal Welfare Institute (Box 65)
    - "Comfortable Quarters for Laboratory Animals," 1958 (Box 65)
    - "Information Report," 1952-1981, (2 folders) (Box 65)
    - Miscellany, 1951-2001, (3 folders) (Box 66)
    - "Physical and Mental Suffering of Experimental Animals," 1979 (Box 66)
  - Animal welfare "personalities," 1953-1999, (3 folders) (Box 66)
  - Animal welfare "personalities," 1953-1999 (Box 67)
  - Animal welfare societies (Box 67)
    - Canada, 1976-1978 (Box 67)
    - International, 1958-1992, (3 folders) (Box 67)
    - United States, 1945-2004 (Box 67)
    - United States, 1945-2004, (6 folders) (Box 68)
    - United States, 1945-2004 (Box 69)
    - Virginia, 1958-1999, (2 folders) (Box 69)
  - Animals, antibiotics, 1966-1973, (3 folders) (Box 69)
  - Animals, disease, 1976-1978 (Box 69)
  - Animals, military, 1967-1994, (2 folders) (Box 70)
  - Animals, movies, 1982 (Box 70)
  - Animals, religion, 1945-2000, (4 folders) (Box 70)
  - Animals, religion, 1945-2000, (4 folders) (Box 71)
  - Animals, reproductive physiology, 1968-1983 (Box 71)
  - Animals, research, 1959-1998, (3 folders) (Box 71)
  - Animals, research, 1959-1998, (5 folders) (Box 72)
  - Animals, transportation of, 1958-1979, (2 folders) (Box 72)
  - Animals, transportation of, 1958-1979, (3 folders) (Box 73)
  - Anthropology and paleontology, 1958-1994, (2 folders) (Box 73)
  - Anthropology and paleontology, 1958-1994 (Box 74)
  - Argus Archives, 1970-1978, (2 folders) (Box 74)
  - "Around the world with Ann and Verna," 1941-1948 (Box 74)
  - Arthurdale, W. Va., fiftieth anniversary, 1977, 1984 (Box 74)
  - Asia, Central, 1953-1954, (2 folders) (Box 74)
  - Attitudes toward animals (Box 74)
    - Children, 1965-1996 (Box 74)
    - Cruelty, 1959-2003, (6 folders) (Box 75)
    - Cruelty, 1959-2003 See also OV 2, same heading, (5 folders) (Box 76)
    - Double standards, 1978-1999 (Box 76)
    - Media, 1959-1997 (Box 76)
    - Media, 1959-1997, (6 folders) (Box 77)
    - Media, 1959-1997, (2 folders) (Box 78)
    - Miscellany, 1956-1999, (4 folders) (Box 78)
    - Miscellany, 1956-1999, (3 folders) (Box 79)
  - Auburn University, Auburn, Ala., donations for animal research, 1968-1976 (Box 79)
  - Back Bay Wildlife Refuge, Virginia Beach, Va., 1970-1972, (2 folders) (Box 79)
  - Bats, 1981-1989 (Box 79)
  - Bears, 1983-1995 (Box 79)
  - Beauty Without Cruelty, 1975-1998 (Box 79)
  - Beef and cattle, 1958-2000, (7 folders) (Box 80)
  - Belle Grove, Middletown, Va., 1982-1983 (Box 81)
  - Between the Species, 1987-1989 (Box 81)
  - Birds (Box 81)
    - Blackbirds, 1975-1976, (3 folders) (Box 81)
    - Doves and pigeons, 1945-1996, (2 folders) (Box 81)
    - Miscellany, 1959-1997 (Box 81)
    - Miscellany, 1959-1997, (4 folders) (Box 82)
    - Wild Bird Conservation Act, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 82)
  - Book publishers and distributors, 1980, 1987-1989 (Box 82)
  - Book publishers and distributors, 1980, 1987-1989 (Box 83)
  - "Brief History of the White House," undated (Box 83)
  - Bryant, Anita, circa 1977 (Box 83)
  - Brisk, Fay; Salamone, Constantina, 1963-1989 (Box 83)
  - Bullette, Jackie, 1982-1984 (Box 83)
  - Burgess, Thornton W., 1965-1974 (Box 83)
  - Cambodia; Vietnam, 1946-1967, (3 folders) (Box 83)
  - Cambodia; Vietnam, 1946-1967 (Box 84)
  - Cancer, 1954-1988, (2 folders) (Box 84)
  - Cannan, Keith, 1965-1968 (Box 84)
  - Carson, Rachel (Box 84)
    - Animals, 1962-1963 (Box 84)
    - Anniversaries, 1969-2002 (Box 84)
    - Articles and writings by Free (Box 84)
      - Articles, 1960-1989, undated (Box 84)
      - "Great Awakening," 1969-1970 (Box 84)
      - "Little Woman Who Started It All," 1969, 1980, 1987-1988 (Box 84)
      - "Little Woman Who Started It All," 1969, 1980, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 85)
      - "Magic of Rachel Carson," 1919-1920, 1963, 1971, 1995-1999, (5 folders) (Box 85)
      - "Rescuing the Rachel Carson Wildlife Refuge," 1987-1989 (Box 86)
      - Rough drafts, 1970-1972, 1987, undated (Box 86)
      - "Since Silent Spring," 1992-1994, (2 folders) (Box 86)
      - "Unpublished," 1969-1970, undated (Box 86)
    - Articles and writings by others, 1951-1999, (2 folders) (Box 86)
    - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University, 1987-1991 (Box 87)
    - Biographical sketches, 1921, 1933, 1963, 1991 (Box 87)
    - Briggs, Shirley A., 1963-1990 (Box 87)
    - Childhood, 1919-1937 (Box 87)
    - Chilton, Edward M., 1966, 1992-1993 (Box 87)
    - Correspondence (Box 87)
      - Carson and Ann Cottrell Free, 1959 (Box 87)
      - Carson and Christine Stevens, 1959-1963, 1969 (Box 87)
      - Carson and Dorothy Freeman, 1953-1978, 1993 (Box 87)
      - Miscellany, 1959-2000, (2 folders) (Box 87)
    - Critics, 1962-1965, 1988 (Box 87)
    - Honors to Carson, 1962-1999 (Box 87)
    - Honors to Free, 1970, 1987-2000 (Box 87)
    - "Interagency Coordination in Environmental Hazards," hearings, 1963, May-June (Box 88)
    - "Kudos" to Free, 1962, 1969-1980, 1988-1992 (Box 88)
    - Last will and testament, 1964 (Box 88)
    - Legacy and obituaries, 1928-1932, 1964-2007 (Box 88)
    - "Letters from Rachel Carson: A Young Scientist Sets Her Course" by Dorothy Thompson Self, 1987 (Box 88)
    - Miscellany, 1949-1999 (Box 88)
    - Rachel Carson Council, 1967-2004, (2 folders) (Box 88)
    - Rachel Carson Council, 1967-2004, (2 folders) (Box 89)
    - Rachel Carson Homestead Association, 1972-1999 (Box 89)
    - Rachel Carson National Wildlife Refuge, Wells, Maine, 1969-1977, 1986-1999, (3 folders) (Box 89)
    - Rachel Carson National Wildlife Refuge, Wells, Maine, 1969-1977, 1986-1999 (Box 90)
    - "Recent," 1970, 1994-2002 (Box 90)
    - Schweitzer, Albert, 1963, 1970-1978, 1987-1990 (Box 90)
    - Silent Spring (Box 90)
      - Articles, 1962-1998 (Box 90)
      - Copy inscribed by Carson to Free, 1962 (Box 90)
    - Society of Woman Geographers, 1951, 1986-1987 (Box 90)
    - Speeches by Carson, 1962-1963 (Box 90)
    - Speeches by Free, 1965-1969, 1987-1999 (Box 90)
    - Speeches by Free, 1965-1969, 1987-1999 (Box 91)
  - Cats, 1942-1999, (2 folders) (Box 91)
  - Chennault, Anna, 1970-1971 (Box 91)
  - Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, 1970-1971 (Box 91)
  - China (Box 91)
    - Articles and writings by Free (Box 91)
      - Articles, 1943-1967, (3 folders) (Box 91)
      - "China Between," outline and notes, 1968 (Box 92)
      - "China book" (Box 92)
        - Complete manuscript, 1946-1947, circa 1990s, (4 folders) (Box 92)
        - "Excess," 1946-1947, 1999-2002, (2 folders) (Box 92)
        - First draft, 1946, circa 1990s (Box 92)
        - First draft, 1946-1947, circa 1990s, (3 folders) (Box 93)
        - "Master," full collection of letters and diaries, 1946-1947, circa 1990s, (3 folders) (Box 93)
        - Notes, 1999-2001 (Box 93)
        - Outline, 1984 (Box 94)
        - Publication idea; United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, 1990-2000 (Box 94)
      - "China, Then," prospectus, 1969 (Box 94)
      - Famine, 1946, 1966 (Box 94)
      - "Flee Down the Night," circa 1950s, (2 folders) (Box 94)
      - "Novel material," 1954-1960, (2 folders) (Box 94)
      - Shanghai, 1946-1952 (Box 94)
      - Zhou, Enlai; Deng, Yingchao, 1942-1946, 1972 See also OV 2, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Britton, Anne C., 1992, 2000 (Box 95)
    - Chen, Jack, 1947, 1973-1986, 1995 (Box 95)
    - Chiang, May-ling Soong, 1965-1966, 1995 (Box 95)
    - Communism; Mao, Zedong, 1947-1975, 1994, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1947, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1947, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - Diaries, 1946-1947, (5 folders) (Box 96)
    - Diaries, 1946-1947, 2001 (Box 97)
    - Harbin, 1946 (Box 97)
    - Miscellany, 1946-2001, (4 folders) (Box 97)
    - Nuclear weapons, 1953, 1966-1969 (Box 97)
    - Pamphlets, 1945-1946, undated, (2 folders) (Box 97)
    - Shanghai, 1945-2002 (Box 98)
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA) (Box 98)
      - Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 98)
      - History, 1945-1947, 2000-2004, (3 folders) (Box 98)
      - Miscellany, 1943-1948, 1976, 1985 (Box 98)
      - Office and personnel files, 1944-1947 (Box 98)
      - Office and personnel files, 1944-1947 (Box 99)
    - "Women in China," Anna Louise Strong, Betty Graham, 1948-1992 (Box 99)
    - Woodcuts of War-Time China: 1937-1945, 1949 (Box 99)
    - Zhou, Enlai; Deng, Yingchao, 1946-1989 See also OV 5, same heading (Box 99)
  - Civil rights, 1940-2002, (2 folders) (Box 99)
  - Committee for Humane Legislation, 1974-1977, 1986-1988 (Box 99)
  - County fairs, 1972-1995 (Box 99)
  - "Declaration on the Rights of Animals," 1988-1990 See also OV 2, same heading (Box 100)
  - De Croÿ, Elisabeth; Refuge de Thiernay, La Fermeté, France, 1981-2006, (3 folders) (Box 100)
  - Deep Run Hunt Club, Richmond, Va.; Fox hunting, 1931-1997, (2 folders) (Box 100)
  - Defenders of Animal Rights, 1976-1983 (Box 100)
  - Delineator (publication), 1905, Sept. (Box 100)
  - Delta Society, 1982-1991 (Box 100)
  - Democratic National Convention, New York, N.Y., 1976, July 12-15 (Box 101)
  - Department of Agriculture, 1959-1998 (Box 101)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1951-1967 (Box 101)
  - Diner, Jeff, undated (Box 101)
  - "Diplomat List," Department of State, 1941, Aug. (Box 101)
  - "Dismissal of Bob Burke: Heidelberg Comes to Columbia," circa 1936 (Box 101)
  - Dog pounds, Washington, D.C., 1953-1988, (4 folders) (Box 101)
  - Dogs, 1959-2002, (2 folders) (Box 101)
  - Dogs, 1959-2002, (6 folders) (Box 102)
  - Drug use guides for animals, 1971-1976 (Box 102)
  - Dulles, Eleanor Lansing, 1953-1954 (Box 102)
  - Duvin, Ed; Animalines (publication), 1987-1991 (Box 102)
  - Ecology, nature, and biology, 1963-1990, (6 folders) (Box 103)
  - Egypt; Israel; Palestine, 1945-1947 See also OV 2, same heading (Box 103)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.; Humane slaughter bill, 1958, 1991-1992 (Box 104)
  - Elephants, 1968-2005, (2 folders) (Box 104)
  - Endangered species, 1968-1998, (4 folders) (Box 104)
  - Endangered species, 1968-1998, (4 folders) (Box 105)
  - Energy, 1973-1989, (2 folders) (Box 105)
  - Energy, 1973-1989, (3 folders) (Box 106)
  - Environmental concerns, 1957-2000, (3 folders) (Box 106)
  - Environmental concerns, 1957-2000, (6 folders) (Box 107)
  - Environmental concerns, 1957-2000, (5 folders) (Box 108)
  - Environmental conservation, 1968-1994 (Box 108)
  - Environmental conservation, 1968-1994, (4 folders) (Box 109)
  - Ethics and animals, 1963-1996, (2 folders) (Box 109)
  - Ethics and animals, 1963-1996, (5 folders) (Box 110)
  - "Ethics for Future Humankind: An Animal Rights Reader" by Allan Cate and Karen Davis, circa 1980s (Box 111)
  - Ethology, 1961-1987, (3 folders) (Box 111)
  - Euthanasia, 1960-1997, (2 folders) (Box 111)
  - Euthanasia, 1960-1997 See also OV 5, same heading, (4 folders) (Box 112)
  - Evans, Alice, 1988, 1995 (Box 112)
  - Factory farms, 1965-1998, (2 folders) (Box 112)
  - Factory farms, 1965-1998, (3 folders) (Box 113)
  - Family farms, 1950-1977 (Box 113)
  - Federation of Homemakers, 1959-1968 (Box 113)
  - Fertilizers, 1974-1978 (Box 113)
  - Fighting animals, 1960-2003, (2 folders) (Box 113)
  - First Presbyterian Church, Tuscaloosa, Ala., church memory book, 1933 (Box 114)
  - Fish, 1964-1999, (2 folders) (Box 114)
  - Food (Box 114)
    - Baby formula, 1978-1979 (Box 114)
    - Cooking, 1953-1988, (3 folders) (Box 114)
    - Cooking, 1953-1988, (3 folders) (Box 115)
    - Crops, grains, and weather, 1971-1978, (2 folders) (Box 115)
    - Fast food, 1973-1980, (2 folders) (Box 115)
    - Meat, 1958-2003, (4 folders) (Box 116)
    - Nutrition, 1961-2002, (2 folders) (Box 116)
    - Nutrition, 1961-2002 (Box 117)
    - Protein and cholesterol, 1966-1978 (Box 117)
  - Food for Peace, 1961 (Box 117)
  - Forests and trees, 1963-1992 (Box 117)
  - Foundation for Biomedical Research, 1996 (Box 117)
  - France, travel, 1982-1986 (Box 117)
  - Friends of Africa in America, 1969-1970 (Box 117)
  - Friends of Animals, 1971-1990 (Box 117)
  - Fund for Animals, 1972-2004 (Box 117)
  - Fund for Animals, 1972-2004, (2 folders) (Box 118)
  - Fur, 1948-1999, (4 folders) (Box 118)
  - Furman, Bess, 1934-1943, 1956-1963, 1982, 2000 (Box 118)
  - Genetics, 1967-1996 (Box 119)
  - Glasgow, Ellen, 1941-2004, (4 folders) (Box 119)
  - Glover-Archbold Park, Washington, D.C., 1953-1970, (2 folders) (Box 119)
  - Glover-Archbold Park, Washington, D.C., 1953-1970, (3 folders) (Box 120)
  - Goodall, Jane, 1984-2001, (2 folders) (Box 120)
  - Grandin, Temple, 1958, 1975-1980, (2 folders) (Box 120)
  - Grandin, Temple, 1976-1980 See also OV 5, same heading (Box 121)
  - Greenpeace, 1978-1986 (Box 121)
  - Great Old Broads for Wilderness, 1991-1993 (Box 121)
  - "Guide to Understanding Internationals," circa 1970s (Box 121)
  - Halle, Louis J., 1961-1970 (Box 121)
  - Harrison, Ruth, 1966-1977, 1990-2001 (Box 121)
  - Hemlock Society of the National Capital Area, 1997-1999 (Box 121)
  - Henry and Annie Hurt Home for the Blind; Hardy, Warren, 1940-1997, (3 folders) (Box 121)
  - Henry and Annie Hurt Home for the Blind; Hardy, Warren, 1940-1997, (4 folders) (Box 122)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1999, undated (Box 122)
  - Hobby, Oveta Culp, 1952-1960 (Box 122)
  - Hornaday, Mary (Box 122)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1950, 1969-1974, undated, (2 folders) (Box 122)
    - Diaries, 1924-1927, 1938, undated, (2 folders) (Box 123)
    - Miscellany, 1920, 1982, undated See also OV 2, same heading (Box 123)
    - Photographs, 1937, 1945-1961, undated, (4 folders) (Box 123)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 124)
    - Willis, Raymond E., campaign scrapbook, circa 1938-1940 See also OV 2, same heading (Box 124)
    - Writings, circa 1932, 1945-1974, undated (Box 124)
  - Horses, donkeys, and mules, 1917-2003, (5 folders) (Box 124)
  - Horses, donkeys, and mules, 1917-2003, (6 folders) (Box 125)
  - Horses, donkeys, and mules, 1917-2003, (3 folders) (Box 126)
  - Hosum, John, 1977-1978 (Box 126)
  - Houghton, Dorothy Deemer, 1954 (Box 126)
  - Human Animal Liberation Front, 1988-1989 (Box 126)
  - "Humane education," 1955-1998, (2 folders) (Box 126)
  - "Humane education," 1956-1998, (6 folders) (Box 127)
  - "Humane education," 1956-2002, (4 folders) (Box 128)
  - Humane News, 1986-1990 (Box 129)
  - Humane slaughter, 1940-2000, (6 folders) (Box 129)
  - Humane slaughter, 1940-2000, (6 folders) (Box 130)
  - Humane Society of the United States (Box 131)
    - Albert Schweitzer Animal Welfare Suggestion Fund, 1981-1992, (7 folders) (Box 131)
    - Albert Schweitzer Animal Welfare Suggestion Fund, 1993-1999, (5 folders) (Box 132)
    - Albert Schweitzer Animal Welfare Suggestion Fund, 1999-2003, (3 folders) (Box 133)
    - Civil action no. 3627-70, circa 1971, (2 folders) (Box 133)
    - Fox, Michael W.; Stephens, Martin, 1983-1986 (Box 133)
    - Humane Society of the United States News, 1958-1976, (2 folders) (Box 134)
    - Kindness Club, 1958-1989, (2 folders) (Box 134)
    - Kindness in Nature's Defense (KIND), 1970-1994, (2 folders) (Box 134)
    - Kindness in Nature's Defense (KIND), 1970-1994 (Box 135)
    - Kindness in Nature's Defense Teaching Tips, 1974-1976 (Box 135)
    - Miscellany, 1957-1970s, (4 folders) (Box 135)
    - Miscellany, 1970s-2002, undated, (6 folders) (Box 136)
    - Miscellany, 1990-2002, undated, (3 folders) (Box 137)
    - "Why you are a humanitarian" survey, undated (Box 137)
  - Hunting, 1935-2002, (3 folders) (Box 137)
  - Hunting, 1935-2002, (6 folders) (Box 138)
  - Hunting, 1935-2002, (6 folders) (Box 139)
  - Iacobbo, Karen, 1987-1990 (Box 139)
  - In Defense of Animals, 1973-1997 (Box 140)
  - India, 1938-1966, 1985, 1997-1998, (3 folders) (Box 140)
  - Institute of Laboratory Animal Resources, 1958-1966, (2 folders) (Box 140)
  - Institute of Laboratory Animal Resources, 1958-1966, (2 folders) (Box 141)
  - International Primate Protection League, 1975-1999, (4 folders) (Box 141)
  - International Society for Animal Rights, 1991-1996 (Box 141)
  - Iranian Student's Association in Washington-Baltimore, circa 1975 (Box 141)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Box 141)
    - Beagles, 1964 (Box 141)
    - Pen, circa 1967 (Box 142)
  - Jones, Helen E., 1960-1980, 1992-1998 (Box 142)
  - Kangaroos, 1974-1985 (Box 142)
  - Katcher, Gladys, 1978, 2000 (Box 142)
  - Keller, Helen, 1960-1965 (Box 142)
  - Kennedy, Ethel, horse case, 1966-1971 (Box 142)
  - Kerr, Robert, 1950-1961 (Box 142)
  - Knight, Frances G., 1955 (Box 142)
  - La Joie, 1990-2000 (Box 142)
  - Laboratory animals (Box 142)
    - Articles and writings by Free, 1962-1981 (Box 142)
    - Bills and legislation, 1960-1965, (2 folders) (Box 142)
    - Bills and legislation, 1966-1969, (3 folders) (Box 143)
    - Caged animals, 1960-1995, (2 folders) (Box 143)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1972, 1987, 1992-1994 (Box 143)
    - Department of Agriculture, 1984-1985, 1999 (Box 143)
    - Food and Drug Administration (Box 143)
      - Articles and writings by Free, 1959-1971, undated (Box 143)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1973 (Box 143)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1973 (Box 144)
      - Miscellany, 1953-1993, (4 folders) (Box 144)
    - Miscellany, 1956-2000, (2 folders) (Box 144)
    - Miscellany, 1956-2000, (4 folders) (Box 145)
  - Laboratory Animals Centre; Vegetarian Society, Manchester, England, 1966-1978 (Box 145)
  - Lacey, John Fletcher, 1972-1979 (Box 145)
  - Lacey, John Fletcher, 1972-1979 (Box 146)